[grunting]
[thwacking]
What a dummy.
[exhaling]
Oh, Master.
[Nagakura]
At it again, training so early?
My apologies.
Did I wake you?
Nah.
Don't overdo it.
Your hands are all torn up.
[sighs]
[Sasaki] Master.
[Nagakura] Hm?
I'm sorry to impose, but...
I'd be grateful
for your instruction.
What are you talking about?
You're plenty strong already.
There's nothing more
I can teach you.
[exclaims softly]
[♪♪♪]
You're the only master I'll
ever have, Nagakura Shinpachi.
Cut it out.
Spare me the flattery.
It's not flattery.
You accepted your own
lack of natural talent
and overcame it with nothing
but pure hard work.
The way you became
this strong...
you're my inspiration, Master.
[scoffs]
No talent, no talent...
You've got some nerve.
I can't tell
if you're complimenting me
or insulting me.
My apologies.
Whatever.
It's the truth, anyway.
[grunts]
You've gotten good
at that disarming technique.
All thanks to you, Master.
Bring it.
This "talentless" senior
will give you a lesson.
Thank you very much.
[insects chirring]
Half past six. I'll be
waiting at Shinkenji Temple.
Guess who?
[sword slices]
[blood spilling]
[grunts]
[coughs]
THE CORPS CODE
[yelling]
[grunting]
[blows landing]
[coughs]
Come on, Shimada.
What's the matter?
Put more spirit into it.
[gasping]
My apologies, Vice-Commander.
[Okita]
Hijikata doesn't hold back.
[Kondo]
Face every opponent
with everything you've got.
It's the only way to show
true respect for your opponent.
[grunting]
[♪♪♪]
[groans]
[groaning]
[Okita]
But they are all intimidated.
[student 1]
He's just too damn strong.
[student 2]
He's making Shimada
look like a child...
Out of the way!
[Hijikata]
Heisuke, we're practicing.
This is no time for that!
Aijiro...
Aijiro has been killed!
[indistinct chatter]
[doshin]
Back off.
Back off. Come on.
[♪♪♪]
Hey!
[crowd exclaiming]
SONG OF THE SAMURAI
Are you sure it was Aijiro?
Yes.
According to
the magistrate's office,
the body had countless
sword wounds.
They said the fatal wound
was being run through
from back to stomach.
Does Shinpachi know?
No idea.
Haven't seen Nagakura
at the dojo today.
Any idea who did it?
No idea.
The magistrate's office thinks
it was probably a robber
since his belongings were taken.
A robber?
No way he'd be killed
by a common thief.
[footsteps approaching]
[Niimi]
Coming in.
What do you want, Niimi?
I hear one of your men
got himself killed.
I see you get news quickly.
Our faction's full of new blood,
you see.
Can't have them losing morale
over something trivial.
Trivial?
The way he died.
Get it right.
His name was Sasaki Aijiro.
Ah?
There is no one in this corps
named "the guy who got killed."
[scoffs]
Killed by a common thief,
I hear.
A weakling like that isn't even
worth learning the name of.
You bastard...
How dare you insult
a fallen comrade?
One...
If you fail to kill
and take a wound to your back,
it is seppuku.
This Sasaki...
whatever his name was...
was cut down
while turning his back.
He'd have had to commit seppuku
even if he had survived.
That's the Corps Code, isn't it?
Kondo.
One of your men has disgraced
the name of the Mibu Roshigumi.
How are you going to answer
for this?
Hey, Niimi.
[Nagakura]
Stop, Toshi.
Shinpachi.
What he's saying is bullshit.
There's no way Aijiro
would turn his back
on some common thief.
In that case...
who do you claim did it?
I don't know,
but I'll find whoever it is.
I'll find the bastard...
and finish them.
THE CORPS CODE
ONE, IF YOU FAIL TO KILL
AND TAKE A WOUND TO YOUR BACK,
IT IS SEPPUKU
[sighs]
[screams]
[footsteps approaching]
[Seiki]
What's up? Bye.
[♪♪♪]
Couldn't resist
causing some trouble, huh?
You think I overdid it?
There's nothing like picking
on the weak, is there?
I just get so into it.
Ha-ha!
Whatever.
[coin clinks]
Whoa, damn.
Are you sure I should get
this much for that little thing?
But are you sure about this?
The truth is, I was ordered
to assassinate Kondo Isami
so I went undercover with them.
That's not your place
to worry about.
Right.
So, what's next?
You've done enough.
[laughing]
For real?
You think taking out one grunt
is enough to bring down Kondo?
Ah.
You're a true strategist, Niimi.
Just what I'd expect.
Guess I'll use this cash
to celebrate.
Surely.
You didn't mess up?
Of course not.
You were listening,
weren't you, Yamazaki?
Money, money, money!
Money! Money!
Keep an eye on him.
Yes.
Move.
Welcome.
Hey.
Skipping patrol to go drinking?
Must be nice.
Crap. I got busted.
[chuckles]
And you're not even wearing
your damn coat.
You're not taking this
seriously?
[laughs]
No, no, no, of course I am!
Nagakura, you came
all the way out here...
So aren't you slacking off too?
Won't you have a drink with me?
Forget that. Saeki...
It's about Aijiro.
[laughing]
Heard he got killed
by some thugs, right?
Here.
[chuckles]
Thanks.
I saw his body.
The fatal blow
one strike from back to stomach.
The style of the sword strike
was Shindo Munen-ryu.
That's your style too, isn't it?
[drink continues pouring]
What's more, you're from Choshu.
What a waste!
You're the one
who killed Aijiro.
[laughing]
Whoa, what is this
all of a sudden?
Why would I go and kill
one of our own comrades?
Besides, there must be
a thousand swordsmen in Kyo
who use that style.
Including you, right, Nagakura?
Anyway, I already deserted
the Choshu clan.
What happened to your finger?
Ah... Ha-ha.
A girl bit me over
in the pleasure district.
You'd wear a splint for just
a little bite on your pinky?
Aijiro broke it with his
disarming technique, didn't he?
Don't move.
You plan to fight
with that hand?
[sighing]
Ah...
[laughing]
[♪♪♪]
[grunting]
[laughing]
Aah!
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
[laughing]
Even you could see
the huge gap between us, right?
You know...
you're going to get crushed,
so why aren't you running?
So, master and student
are alike, huh? Hilarious.
Let me ask you instead.
Huh?
There's one thing
I just don't get.
Why did you have to kill Aijiro
in such a brutal way?
A man with your skill...
you could have finished him off
in a single blow.
[laughing]
I guess a hack like you
wouldn't get it.
Killing someone
in a crushing win....
feels better
than screwing a woman.
[laughing]
You bastard!
[gasps playfully]
What the hell is that?
Trying to make me die
of laughter?
[laughing]
Don't you mock me!
[yelling fiercely]
And there it is.
A decisive victory.
Now this feels good.
Way too easy.
[grunting]
I can't hold it in anymore.
Sorry, but here I come!
[exclaims]
[flesh squelches]
[chokes]
You know, Saeki...
the real thrill comes...
when you crush someone
far beyond your own skill.
[coughing]
W-Wait! Nagakura, please!
Do you have any proof that
I'm the one who killed Aijiro?
Y-You don't have any, do you?
I'm not sloppy
with things like that.
I-If you finish me off now
the truth about me
being the killer
will just be swept
under the rug.
S-S-So, look! I'll cooperate!
I'll go to the magistrate's
office... anywhere you say.
[crying]
I'll tell you everything I know,
I swear.
Please! Just spare my life!
I see.
Fine.
[sniveling]
Thank you!
Thank you so much.
I'll be in your debt
for the rest of my life.
[blade rings]
Oh?
[blade clatters]
You're such a transparent
piece of shit.
[gasping]
[neck snaps]
[♪♪♪]
[Niimi]
So, Nagakura made his move.
[Yamazaki]
Yes.
Just as I predicted.
The winner is...
Nagakura Shinpachi.
I see.
Saeki was a fool.
For all his talent with a sword,
he let his skill go to his head.
[chuckles]
And with this...
Kondo Isami is finished.
[♪♪♪]
There are no sword wounds
on him.
Unbelievable...
Nagakura...
You beat the best dual-wielder
with just brute force.
Hey. Hey, Shinpachi! Hey, why?
Why'd you try to shoulder this
all alone?
Toshi, what's the problem?
You guys, that scumbag Saeki
is the one who killed Aijiro!
This was righteous revenge!
Right?!
Answer me!
If only there were proof
of that.
Kondo, any luck?
I searched Saeki's belongings
but found no proof
that he killed Sasaki Aijiro.
Hey!
Did you check properly, boss?
Yes.
Nagakura...
why did you pass judgment
on Saeki?
If you passed judgment
on an assumption
then this is
just a private duel
fought for your own
selfish reasons.
Don't tell me
you've forgotten the Corps Code?
One.
Do not engage
in personal fights.
Anyone who violates these
articles must commit seppuku.
I am prepared for that.
[♪♪♪]
Hold on a second!
What do you mean, prepared?!
Hey, Shinpachi!
How did you know
it was Saeki?
At least answer that much.
Everyone...
I'm sorry
for all the trouble.
Hey, Shinpachi...
But I have no regrets.
Knock it off!
[♪♪♪]
Farewell.
Shinpachi!
[wakizashi clatters]
Shinpachi.
You're not meant to fall
in a place like this.
Boss...
Niimi!
I ask that you grant a brief
stay of Shinpachi's seppuku.
[Okita]
Kondo, please stop!
I beg of you!
[Hijikata]
Hey!
[Niimi]
Oh?
So, the Commander himself
would bend the Corps Code.
And you expect to maintain
discipline that way?
Shinpachi's failure is my own.
In his place...
I will resign my position
as Commander.
What are you saying,
boss!
As will I.
I shall resign my post
as vice-commander.
Yamanami...
[laughing heartily]
What is this farce?!
As if that could ever be a fair
trade for Nagakura's seppuku.
Then Nagakura's life
must be pretty damn cheap.
Then...
what do we need to do?
Commit seppuku.
Hey, you bastard! Cut it out!
Who's being ridiculous here?
Anyone who violates the Corps
Codes must commit seppuku!
You're the ones
who made that rule!
[Serizawa exclaiming slowly]
This is a lively bunch.
Niimi, come on,
cut them some slack.
But...
Besides, what's fun
in making them commit seppuku?
[stammers]
Kondo. Yamanami!
You have Serizawa's mercy
to thank for this.
Hey, Niimi. Watch your mouth.
Why would
a Vice-Commander like me
listen to
a rank-and-file soldier?
You rotten country-samurai!
From this moment on,
you're all just common soldiers.
You will all serve
under Serizawa.
That is the condition
for granting Nagakura
a reprieve from seppuku.
Is that acceptable, Serizawa?
I don't care.
Do whatever you want.
[shouts]
[punch thuds]
What the hell are you doing!
Yamanami, you too!
[Niimi]
That was a surprise.
I can't believe
you showed them mercy.
[Serizawa]
Mercy, huh.
[Niimi]
It was the best chance
to take out Kondo, wasn't it?
I don't remember
showing any mercy.
Eh?
Niimi...
If you want to kill,
do it with your own hands.
Seppuku is the most boring thing
in this world.
[yawns]
Serizawa!
I heard the news.
I heard you used the Corps Code
to bring the Kondo faction
under our control.
[chuckles]
That was all Niimi's doing.
Well, well.
I'm impressed, Vice-Commander.
Watch your mouth!
I'm your superior officer.
What example does that set
for our men?
[scoffs]
That's ridiculous.
We're on the same side.
Well, how about we go out
and celebrate bringing the Kondo
faction under our wing?
No.
I think it's about time
for our little festival.
[laughs]
[♪♪♪]
SEPTEMBER 24, 1863
[Hirayama]
We are the Mibu Roshigumi!
[stammering]
Hey, hey, hey!
What's all this about?
[whimpering]
This is an official inspection.
You've cornered the market
on raw silk
and kept all the profits
for yourselves!
It's time you learned
how much suffering
you've caused
the people of this city!
Move out of the way.
This money isn't for you
to line your own pockets with.
It will be used
for the people of Kyo.
Got it?
[men whimpering]
We'll be back.
All right, let's move out.
[soldiers]
Sir!
Now... let's begin.
[laughs]
What are you doing,
Serizawa?
Isn't it obvious?
It's a festival!
Come on, you light one, too.
Do it.
Sir! Bring the fire, you lot!
[men shouting indistinctly]
You need more fire!
Go on! Keep going!
[laughs]
Burn it! Burn more!
Serizawa! We're losing
our source of money!
Look, Niimi.
It just burns.
That's the beauty of it.
[♪♪♪]
For everything to burn...
and turn to ashes.
[laughing]
Serizawa Kamo.
A man I must have.
A moral compass
that points somewhere
beyond good and evil,
profit and loss.
One who has no interest
in money or honor...
is a fascinating man indeed.
Whether or not Serizawa Kamo
sides with us
rests entirely
on your shoulders, Mr. Niimi.
You needn't worry, Mr. Kusaka.
He's just a simple-minded brute.
He doesn't have a shred
of loyalty to the Shogunate.
I'm counting on you.
Our preparations
are all set as well.
[Sanjo]
On this occasion...
[Kusaka]
The day after your men attack
and burn down the Yamato-ya...
The Emperor has announced
he'll lead
the expulsionist faction
in seizing power.
So the signal
to overthrow the shogunate
has finally been given.
We must use this momentum
to eliminate
Matsudaira Katamori!
I'm counting on you, Niimi.
How you drove Kondo Isami
into a corner
the other day
was truly brilliant.
I'll take care of Lord Katamori.
150 Men in the Serizawa faction
are under my direct command.
I can mobilize them
at a moment's notice.
That's very reassuring.
This is for you, Niimi.
Do as you like.
[♪♪♪]
[footsteps]
[panting excitedly]
Money. Money. Money! Money!
You really love money that much?
I do. It's the one thing
that will never betray me.
Found it.
Good, things
are really coming together!
Oume, how about a song?
Certainly.
[Oume playing and singing]
[playing and singing fade]
Serizawa.
[♪♪♪]
What's this?
[loud shouting]
[Todo, chuckling]
You are so loud.
Come on! Bring it on!
[laughs]
Hey, Shimada!
How many times
do I have to tell you?
Don't you have any damn respect
for your seniors?!
My apologies. I'll be sure
to go easy on you next time.
Are you mocking me?!
Hey, you are getting
all worked up.
I mean...
Yeah, I can see
why you're pissed.
You two are the only ones
even training.
Everyone's been sucked
into the Serizawa faction
and now it's just us left
in the Kondo faction.
And the boss gets demoted
to a regular grunt.
This is beyond pathetic!
He's still Kondo,
whether he's the Commander
or not.
I'm sorry.
Don't get all worked up, Soji.
It's not like you.
Besides, I don't exactly hate
that it's just us now.
It's like being
back in the Shieikan dojo.
[sighs]
[Shimada]
One more round, please.
No! I don't want to anymore!
You didn't eat again?
[♪♪♪]
[sighs]
[Kondo]
Shinpachi's not eating?
The boss even got on his hands
and knees to save his life.
Does he even understand that?
Now, now, don't be
so hard on him.
If I can save all of you
by bowing my head to the ground
then I'll gladly grovel
in the dirt all day long.
Cut the noble act.
That might be fine for you
but when our commander,
Kondo Isami, bows his head
it's the same as making
all of us grovel on the ground.
I'm sorry, Toshi.
But...
I feel for Shinpachi.
He couldn't protect Aijiro.
I feel like
he's punishing himself for it.
But we can't
just let this go on!
Hey, Yamanami.
Can't you do
something?!
I'm at
my breaking point.
Hijikata.
I feel the same way.
[shuffling footsteps
approaching]
[Hijikata]
Kanbei.
I need to have a word with you.
[indistinct shouting]
As fired up as ever, I see.
Hijikata. Haven't you heard?
An imperial edict is out.
The Emperor will personally
expel the foreigners.
An imperial edict?
[Yamanami]
Does that mean
that the Imperial Court
is moving to overthrow
the shogunate?
[Hijikata]
So that's why you're all
so on edge.
[Sagawa]
That would plunge Kyo
into chaos once more.
Now, more than ever,
we need the Mibu Roshigumi.
But for a matter
of such importance...
Serizawa
is our head commander.
Head commander!
This man, Serizawa...
is he truly up to the task?
He extorts "donations"
from everyone...
and I hear he even burned down
a silk wholesaler's shop
recently.
Kondo! Yamanami! Hijikata!
What's the matter with you!
He extorts "donations"
from everyone.
Pathetic! Utterly pathetic!
You think I don't know that?!
Don't get cocky with me!
Where has
your samurai spirit gone?
If you let him run wild,
you'll bring shame
on Lord Katamori.
[Matsudaira]
I don't give a damn
about my reputation
My lord!
Don't you dare hold back!
[all]
Sir!
Let's practice!
[all shouting]
Kanbei.
Yes, sir!
I couldn't care less about the
Mibu-Roshi's internal squabbles.
However...
the edict
about the Emperor himself
leading the overthrow
of the shogunate.
It's a forgery.
[Sagawa]
A forgery?
Choshu plans to use
a forged edict to win allies
and pick a fight
with the shogunate.
Those bastards... playing dirty.
Playing dirty?
There's no such thing.
This is war.
[Serizawa clears throat]
Serizawa!
Well now,
sorry to crash the party.
[Aizu retainer]
Hey! You're in the lord's
presence! Stand back!
Move.
Hey, hey,
what the hell's going on?
I'm just saying I have something
to tell the boss.
And you're the ones making
all this damn noise, aren't you?
Huh? What's the deal?
[Matsudaira]
Kamo!
What is it you wanted
to discuss?
Ah... Our very own Niimi
is connected with Choshu.
[♪♪♪]
You bastard!
What the hell are you saying?!
I found this
in Niimi's letterbox.
It's a letter from Kusaka Genzui
of Choshu, addressed to Niimi.
[Serizawa]
It's all written right there.
Saeki Matasaburo is a Choshu
assassin, hired by Niimi.
Saeki is an assassin?
[Serizawa] Yes.
Then...
The whole thing with Aijiro...
Niimi and Choshu
were behind that, too.
Originally, Kondo...
KONDO
...it seems the plan was
to get rid of you.
Ah, right, and by the way...
Niimi killed Abiru Eisaburo too.
So it's revenge for Abiru.
[Matsudaira]
So?
What are you going to do
about Niimi?
Mm... Not a damn thing.
I knew all along
and didn't do anything.
The man's been far too useful
to me.
If that's true, then you're
subject to punishment as well.
I don't care.
My Lord...
This isn't just an internal
squabble between Mibu factions.
I won't let this man
get away with this. Serizawa!
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
I'll cut you down
right here and now.
Yes! Finally took the bait.
Hey Sagawa, don't chicken out
like last time.
[♪♪♪]
Oh...
If you wanna kill me, you better
come at me with all you've got.
Hey, hey.
[Sagawa]
What do you think you're doing?
[chuckles]
Sorry. This one's my fight.
Oh? Gotten a little stronger,
have we?
[both chuckle]
[Yoshiaki Dewa's "Chiruran
Shinsengumi Requiem" playing]